When Eric Prince goes to the CIA and
says, "Yeah, I'll do all these things
for you. We've got assassination squads.
We've got interceptors. We've got boots
on the ground. We'll do anything you
want. I want a billion half dollars."
And then the CIA wires it the next day.
Is it CIA? Not really. Everybody's from
the CIA. Everybody's getting rich. But
the thing is is how do you control
people who don't actually work for you?
You can't.
Can you explain to people what private
intelligence is?
>> Oh, sure. I actually did it for for
several years. Um,
private intelligence really is is what
it sounds like. You're doing exactly
what you did at the CIA, whether it's
analysis or operations. You're just not
using classified information to do it.
And I'll give you an example. Um, I got
a call from a criate billionaire one
time and
he said that
he had one daughter, just one daughter,
who was going to inherit all of his
wealth and she was engaged to this bum,
this Greek criate guy who lived in
London.
And he said, "I don't like this guy. I
don't want this guy anywhere near my
money or my daughter, and I need for you
to find out as much about him as you
possibly can. And I said, "Okay, so uh
what's my budget?" And he gave me a
number. I flew to Cyprus. I I bribed a
police captain,
uh to to give me all the secret police
files.
I flew to London. I did surveillance on
this guy's building.
And finally, it took me about six weeks
of of working full-time. And I I got
back to the billionaire and I said,
"Yeah, he's a bum and he's cheating on
her." So, I said, "First of all, he's
been stealing money from her." And he
used the money to buy some warehouse in
London. And I had satellite pictures of
it from Google Earth or Google Yeah.
Earth. And uh I said, "He's gone in with
with some partners. There's like an
Armenian guy and a Turkish guy." And
they all went in. They're losing money,
but they used your money, I said, "To
buy the place." He told your daughter it
was for something else. And then he just
took the money and bought this
warehouse. So that money's gone. He's
trying to buy a mansion in London
because he thinks as soon as he gets
married, he's going to live happily ever
after. It's all about the money. And I
said, "And besides that, he has multiple
drug arrests." He's like, "What?" And I
said, "Yeah, it was smuggling." He was
smuggling drugs from Israel into Cyprus.
He got caught, got arrested, paid off
some judge, so he was never prosecuted.
Um, the Brits think that he's smuggling
drugs there. So the old man went to his
daughter and he he told her, "You're
being scammed." So that's operationally
private intelligence.
Private analysis is different. It's
actually a lot more fun. So I went into
business for myself
in the years between when I left the LO
in or the year and a half between when I
left the loit in I went to the Senate
Foreign Relations Committee and then I
picked it up again when I left the
Senate Foreign Relations Committee. So,
one of my big I I had three big clients.
I had the ninth largest mutual um sorry,
the ninth largest um hedge fund in the
world. I had a mutual fund and I had the
largest
mining company in the world. And then I
did I did a contract for an oil company
as well. So, they would ask very very
specific questions. Who's going to win
the Romanian municipal elections in
September? I'm like,
I don't know anything about Romania. So,
where do you go? You go to LinkedIn,
right? I'm Orthodox
and everybody in Romania is Orthodox.
So, I send connection requests to every
everybody who looks interesting who
happens to be Orthodox in Romania. It's
like 60 people. and I say, "Hey, I got
this question. You know, one guy gave me
private polling data." So, I said to the
client, and I said, "It would help me in
the in the analysis. It would help me if
I knew why you cared who is going to win
the municipal election." And they said,
"Sure.
We're thinking of buying a silver mine.
And the silver mine is underneath a
village. And to mine the silver, we have
to destroy the whole village.
So if the socialists win, they're not
going to let us do it.
>> And if the conservatives win, they'll
just relocate everybody and we'll just
destroy the thing and take the silver.
And I said, "Well, the polls say the
conservatives are going to win." And so
they bought the mine at the pre-election
price. The conservatives win. They move
everybody out of the village. The
company destroys the village and takes
out billions of dollars worth of silver.
Another one was this one was kind of
funny.
This company, they buy an oil field
um or they they didn't buy it, they
lease an oil field, but they lease it
for like 99 years in Oman, and it's
right on the border with Yemen.
And none of them had any idea at the
time that al-Qaeda controls the border
of Oman and Yemen and you're not going
to be able to get anywhere near that
oil, not within 50 miles of it. So they
they wanted to know
um if the Omanis if they approached the
Omanis and offered to pay for the Omani
military to force al-Qaeda out, would
the Omanis do it or should they just
walk away from this oil lease? So, I
went to Oman. I talked to the minister
of oil and the deputy minister of oil. I
talked to the deputy uh intelligence
service director and I I kind of knew
all these guys like we had met. We
weren't like buddies or anything, but we
had met. So, when I asked for the
appointment through the Omani embassy,
they said yes, yes, come and come and
you know, we'll have a conversation. So,
I went back to the company and I said I
said, "They're going to gouge you, but
they'll push al-Qaeda out of your oil
field." And so, they were able to drill
for the oil. That's what private
intelligence is.
>> So, when you tell stories in that
context, it just it it makes it seem
like you're not makes it seem, you're
like a high-speed private investigator.
>> That's really what it comes down to.
Yes.
>> Are you familiar with Black Cube?
>> No. Nope. don't know that one.
>> They're uh
they're a private intelligence firm that
is staffed by uh they're an Israeli
private intelligence firm that is all
exad guys. Um
>> and they allegedly
>> uh I think David Boy is the head
attorney on the Epstein.
>> Oh, sure.
>> Allegedly David Boy used it on someone.
See, the Israelis have no compunction at
all about violating any law that gets in
their way. And then they say, "What are
you going to do about it?"
>> Yeah. Uh, we'll get there in a second
because I want to I want to ask you, so
you mentioned um private intelligence.
You're not using classified information
to do it is what you said,
>> right?
>> Um, but what about what about when the
agency
works with private intelligence firms?
because I I read um Leon Petta's book
who was CIA director in the Obama
administration as well as Secretary of
Defense,
>> but he he mentioned um he starts talking
about he's like, "One of the first
things I did was shut down this program
that was I forget how he described it,
either controversial or unnecessary or
something like that, but he gave no
detail." And I was like, "What the hell
is he talking about?"
>> So, I look it up and it was the it was a
Blackwater assassination program to go
after targets globally. And long story
short, he ended up outing Eric Prince to
uh the House Intelligence Committee by
name. Eric Prince was operating I guess
as a knock or had a 2011 file.
>> That's why Eric Prince lives in Dubai
now and not in the United States.
>> So I guess my my question to you then is
like I had no idea and also Blackwater
was involved in stealing secrets.
>> Like they had a network of spies. When
you think about Blackwater, you think
about boots on the ground, military
contracts. people know that they ran the
GRS program for CIA, but like what how
how did how would a CIA how would the
CIA work with a contractor like that?
The first thing you do is the contractor
appoints all former CIA people to its
board of directors and then you make the
former head of the counterterrorism
center, Kofheer Black, your vice
president. And then you hire all of
Kofheer's buddies to be the head of your
different divisions. So,
is it CIA? Not really. It's quasi CIA.
Everybody's from the CIA. Everybody's
getting rich, right? Because remember,
post 911, money was literally not an
issue. I I told you in our last
conversation that uh I don't know, four,
five, six days after 911, I went up to
Kofheer Black, again, the head of the
CIS counterterrorism center, and I said,
"Keoffer, I have an idea for an
operation I wanted to pass by you." and
he put up his hands and he says,
"Whatever it is, just do it. I have so
much money I can't possibly spend it
all." And so I did it. So, you know,
when when Eric Prince goes to the CIA
and says, "Yeah, I'll do all these
things for you. We've got assassination
squads. We've got interceptors. We've
got boots on the ground. We'll do
anything you want. I want a billion a
half dollars." And then the CIA wires it
the next day. Then you can do whatever
you want. But the thing is is how do you
control people who don't actually work
for you? You can't. And you risk them
going rogue, which of course they do
because it's their nature. If you're
being if you're being contracted to run
an assassination program,
you're going to go out there and
assassinate people. Well, everybody's
human and you make mistakes and you
convince yourself that, you know, Ahmed
Schmmed is a really bad guy. And
actually, nah, it's a cousin with a
similar name, but you just put a bullet
in this guy's head. Ah, okay. Yeah, you
write a check for 100 grand to his widow
and just move on. And that's not cool.
It's a It's a crime. You can't just go
around murdering people because you
think they might be a bad guy. And so,
Panetta, I never really liked Panetta
just cuz he's not a nice guy, but um but
Panetta was right to shut that down.
Okay. So, um,
what are the what are the legalities
then of a
Blackwater team going out to hit
somebody as if a ground branch team
would? It's is it like I think Title 10,
Title 50,
>> right?
>> One's military, one's CIA. I can't
remember which was which.
>> Actually, the Ninth Circuit Court of
Appeals just ruled on this. I'm going to
say three weeks ago, four weeks ago.
Um because that's that's a legitimate
legal question that you're asking. What
what are the legalities? It's never been
tried before, right? Like the CIA has
permission through the amended version
of Executive Order 1233
to kill anybody in the world who poses a
clear and present danger to the United
States. Okay?
And the CIA is going to decide who's the
clear and present danger. And they're
not going to tell you because you're not
cleared, right? I'm not cleared. You're
we're just gonna have to take their word
for it. But they have the legal
authority to kill people through 1233.
Then they hire these contractors like,
well, we have GRS, we have we have
ground branch and marine branch and air
branch, and we have all these these
teams that are out there killing,
kidnapping, blowing up, you know,
whatever.
but they're not agency personnel.
They just work for these private
companies like Blackwater.
So, is that legal?
And the the Ninth Circuit Court of
Appeals said yes, it's legal. So long as
they have a written contract,
they are acting on behalf of the CIA and
the CIA has presidential authority to
carry out these operations.
Mhm.
That was just decided. And actually, I
got a call from one of the attorneys in
the case and he said, "I have no idea
why nobody in the media gives a
about this decision." And so I I told
them I would write something, but
there's nothing out there. Nobody paid
any attention to this decision.
And it it the reason I paid attention
was because um it was Abu Zubeda who was
the plaintiff in the case. Abu Zuba
said, "These guys tortured me and I want
to sue them.
And the court was like, "Yeah, sorry.
You got tortured." But they were acting
on behalf of the CIA. And the CIA was
legally permitted to torture people, so
you're out of luck.
What's up, guys? Thank you so much for
taking the time to watch the interview.
If you got anything out of this video at
all, please like the video, leave me a
comment, tell me what you thought of the
video, uh, tell me who you'd like to see
on the show. I really appreciate the
support. It goes a long way on these
platforms as you guys know. Most
importantly, I have some excellent
interviews coming up in the future that
I'm really, really excited about. So,
please subscribe to the channel so you
don't miss any of them. But that's it.
Thank you for your support. I really
appreciate it and hope to see you again